Graduate Education, Office of; Records ua410
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of Graduate Education Records
1931-2017
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Office of Graduate Education
ua410
10.42 cubic ft.
This collection contains inactive records from the Office of Graduate Education (previously called the Office of Graduate Studies), which is responsible for the administration of graduate programs at the University.
Administrative History
The Office of Graduate Education has its origins circa 1952, with the appointment of Edgar Flinton as the first Director of Graduate Studies. In the 1960s, the position was retitled "Dean of Graduate Studies." Beginning in 1971, the office was combined with the Office for Research, and was administered by a group of Assistant Deans overseen by the Vice President for Research and Graduate Studies. These offices were separated in the late 1990s.
As of 2017, the Office of Graduate Education is headed by the Vice Provost and Dean for Graduate Studies and operates within the Office of the Provost (Academic Affairs).
Scope and Contents
This collection contains adminstrative records created by the Office of Graduate Education (formerly, the Office of Graduate Studies). Types of materials include: internal memoranda, external correspondence, reports, policy documents, and meeting minutes. The primary topics addressed in this collection are: registration and review of graduate programs, enrollment policies, policies for graduate student assistants, Master's and Doctoral dissertation and thesis policies, hiring for administrative positions, and administration of academic departments.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into 6 series. Series 1 contains archived versions of the website of the Office of Graduate Education. Series 2 contains administrative records covering much of the history of the Office. Series 3 through 6 contain materials organized according to the specific Deans and Assistant Deans responsible for their creation.
Acquisition Information
A portion of this collection was donated by Bob McFarland in 1997.
The remainder of the collection was accessioned from a records storage room maintained by the Office of the Provost. 2016
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Web Archives
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Graduate teaching assistants; Universities and colleges--Graduate work.; Education, Higher--Administration.; Universities and colleges--Accreditation.; Accreditation (Education); Web Archives; Administrative records; Letters (correspondence); Memorandums; UAlbany Academic Administration; State University of New York at Albany; State University of New York at Albany. Office of Graduate Education
- Website for the Office of Graduate Education, 2003 February 4-2017 January 17; 1; 885 Captures
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service. This page includes links to both the university's collection and the Internet Archive's public collection.
  Surface-level crawling of www.albany.edu is performed daily which should includes most top-level webpages. Separate targeted crawls of every albany.edu subdomain are performed monthly to attempt to gather all content. This includes: www.albany.edu, www.rna.albany.edu, www.ctg.albany.edu, www.ualbanysports.com, www.albany.edu/rockefeller, www.albany.edu/cela, www.albany.edu/asrc, m.albany.edu, library.albany.edu, events.albany.edu, cstar.cestm.albany.edu, csda.albany.edu, and alumni.albany.edu
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Web Archives
  - http://www.albany.edu/graduate - University Archives collection, 2013 May 8-2017 January 17 (Web-archive 1)
  - WARC file for http://www.albany.edu/graduate, (please see https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_ARChive for more details), 2013 May 8-2017 January 17 (Warc 1)
  - http://www.albany.edu/graduate - Internet Archive collection, 2003 February 4-2017 January 17 (Web-archive 2)
- Office of the Dean of Graduate Studies, 1946-1998; 1960-1990; 2; 3.93 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records created by various Deans and administrators within the Office of Graduate Studies. Materials include: annual reports (1969-1980), admissions and enrollment data, dissertation and thesis abstracts and approvals, correspondence with academic departments and adminstrators, policy documentation covering a variety of subjects (including program review, dissertation transmittal, and graduate assistantships), official descriptions of graduate programs, budget records, and other administrative documentation.
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1946-1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1950-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1958-1987; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Faculty, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Enrollment Summaries, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Enrollment Data, 1961-1964; 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Doctoral Programs Official Description-Professional, 1961-1962; 1967-1976; 1979; 1981-1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Foreign Language Requirement, 1962; 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Additional Materials from the Education Office, 1962; 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Doctoral Dissertation Abstracts and Approvals, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Processing Doctoral Dissertations- Departmental Procedures, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Policies for Program proposals and evaluation, 1963; 1967-1970; 1972-1974; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Master's Degree: Requirements and Thesis, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Graduate Faculty- Agenda, proposals, minutes, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - List of Program Evaluations, 1964-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Undergraduates in Graduate Courses, 1965; 1967-1969; 1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Graduate Programs Guidelines, Policies, and Information, 1966; 1968-1969; 1972-1973; 1975; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Additional Materials from the School of Business, 1966; 1971-1973; 1975; 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Doctoral Programs Official Description- Arts and Sciences (1 of 3), 1966-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Doctoral Programs Official Description- Arts and Sciences (2 of 3), 1966-1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Doctoral Programs Official Description- Arts and Sciences (3 of 3), 1966-1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Office of Graduate Studies- Organization, 1967; 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - French Assistantship Programs, 1967; 1968; 1969; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Wurzburg Program, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Department of Curriculum-Instruction, 1967-1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Admissions and Enrollment summaries, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Additional Materials from the College of Arts and Sciences, 1967; 1969; 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Additional Materials from the Astronomy and Space Science Department, 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Masters Programs Official Descriptions- Professional, 1967-1974; 1976-1979; 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Masters Programs Official Descriptions- Arts and Science, 1967-1979; 1982-1983; 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Masters Programs Official Descriptions- Arts and Science, Graduate School of Public Affairs, 1967-1978; 1980; 1982-1983; 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Masters Programs Official Descriptions- Arts and Science, Graduate School of Public Affairs, 1967-1978; 1980; 1982-1983; 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Certification- Educational Administration, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Memoranda to Deans, Chairmen, faculty, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Materials Distributed, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Office of Graduate Studies, Report for the Academic Year, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Department of Biological Sciences, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Policies on Admission of SUNYA employees as graduate students, 1968; 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Deans- SUNY and USA, 1968; 1969; 1971; Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - School of Education, 1968; 1971; 1972; Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Additional Materials from the Afro-American Studies Department, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Innovative Graduate Programs, 1968; 1973; 1974; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Graduate Assistantships and Fellowships, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Department of Music, 1969; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Materials Distributed, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Memoranda to Deans, Chairmen, faculty, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Office of Graduate Studies, Report for the Academic Year, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Department of Classics, 1969; 1970; 1971; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Credit Hours in Graduate Courses, 1969; 1970; 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Additional Materials from the Office of Undergraduate Studies, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Masters Programs Official Descriptions-Professional, 1969-1975; 1977-1978; 1980-1983; 1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Office of Graduate Admissions, 1969; 1972-1977; 1980; 1982-1986; Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Committee on Training Graduate Teaching Assistants, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Doctoral Programs Under Review, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Office of Graduate Studies, Report for the Academic Year, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Full- Time Study Requirement-Employment, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Materials Distributed, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Grading- Graduate Audit Policies, 1970; 1971; 1973; 1974; Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Self-Study Report in Preparation for the Accrediting Visitation by Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1971 January (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - The Effect of Undergraduate S/U Type Grades on Graduate Admissions and on financial Award Decisions, 1971 November (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Current Projects, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Masters Thesis Abstracts, 1971; 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Office of Graduate Studies and Research, Report for the Academic Year, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Doctoral Degrees Conferred, Summaries, 1971; 1972; 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fact Book on Higher Education (1 of 2), 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fact Book on Higher Education (2 of 2), 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Doctor of Arts, 1971; 1972; 1973; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Graduate Assistantships and Fellowships, Information, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Memoranda to Deans and Department Chairs, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Organization of the Office of Graduate Studies and Research, 1971; 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Additional Materials from the Vice President of Management and Planning, 1971; 1972; 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Additional Materials from the Graduate School of Public Affairs, 1971; 1975; 1977; 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Dissertation Load- Registration Policy, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Doctoral Recipients from United States Universities, 1972; 1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Offices of Graduate Studies and Research, Report for the Academic Year, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Manuals for Graduate Students(1 of 3), 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Manuals for Graduate Students(2 of 3), 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Manuals for Graduate Students(3 of 3), 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Summaries of Graduate Student Support by School and Department, 1972; 1973; 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Report on International Education, 1972; 1974; Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Department of Sociology, 1972; 1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Graduate Education at SUNY Albany, A Summary Report, 1973 April (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Annual Report of the Offices of Graduate Studies and Research, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Program Evaluation, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Departmental and faculty Productivity-Sciences, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Doctoral Program Summaries, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Doctoral Dissertation Abstracts, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Bibliography of Doctoral Theses completed at State University of New York at Albany, 1974 May (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Individualized Graduate Program, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Annual Report of the Offices of Graduate Studies and Research, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Review of Graduate Programs-Procedures,etc., 1974; 1975; Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - State Education Department Evaluations-Criteria and Procedures, 1974-1976; Undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Thesis Requirements, 1974; 1977-1979; Undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Annual Report of the Offices of Graduate Studies and Research, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Master Plans-Graduate Studies, 1975; 1977; 1979 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Annual Report of the Offices of Graduate Studies, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Library and S.E.D. Reviews, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - S.E.D. Certification in Reading, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Annual Report of the Office of Graduate Studies, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Graduate Study-Informational materials, ca. 1977/1978 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - New Format for Graduate Publications, 1977-1980; Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Annual Report of the Office of Graduate Studies, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Updates of Three-Year Plan, 1978; 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Assistantship and Fellowship, Information, 1978-1982; 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Office of Graduate Studies, Report for the Academic Year, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Five Year Plan Progress Updates(1 of 2), 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Five Year Plan Progress Updates(2 of 2), 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - CGS/GRE Survey of Graduate Enrollment, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Department of Counseling and Personnel Services- Program Information, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - NSF Conference- Washington, D.C., 1970 May 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Account Expenditure Summaries - Office of Graduate Admissions and Policy, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Account Expenditure Summaries - Office of Graduate Admissions and Policy, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Account Expenditure Summaries - Office of Graduate Admissions and Policy, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Account Expenditure Summaries - Office of Graduate Admissions and Policy, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Account Expenditure Summaries - Office of Graduate Admissions and Policy, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Account Expenditure Summaries - Office of Graduate Admissions and Policy, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Account Expenditure Summary - Office of Graduate Admissions and Policy, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Records of Edgar Flinton, Dean, 1931-1975; 1960-1975; 3; 2.17 cubic ft.
  This series contains records created by Edgar Flinton, who served as Director of Graduate Studies starting in 1953, and then as Dean of Graduate Studies from 1964 until 1971. Included in this series are correspondence with the State Education Department regarding program registration and evaluation, materials from meetings of the Graduate Faculty, planning documentation, memoranda to Deans and Department Chairs, budget documentation (including allocations for graduate fellowships and assistantships), and other assorted correspondence, reports, and meeting minutes.
  - A Report on Some Phases of Graduate Study in The New York State College For Teachers at Albany, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New York State Education Department- Registration of Graduate Programs, 1954; 1957-1958; 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Registration- State Education Department, 1954; 1958; 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Certification-Policy, 1957-1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programs Registered with State Education Department, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Teacher Preparation Programs, 1958-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Certification-Guidance, 1959; 1961; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Graduate Office- Plans, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Certification- Documents, 1961; 1962; 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum, Supervision, and Instruction, Ed. D., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Guidance and Personnel Services, State-Wide Coordinating Committee, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Certification-State Education Department Guidelines, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Guidance and Personnel Services Program, 1962; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, 1962; 1964; 1965; Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Provost, State University of New York-Harry Porter-Registration of Programs, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Graduate Programs- Planning, Correspondence with Harry Porter, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Internships, 1963; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Memoranda to Deans, Chairman, Faculty, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Course Proposal and Approval- Procedures, 1963; 1965; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Provost, State University of New York Harry Porter, 1963; 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Program proposals and evaluation, 1963; 1966-1968; 1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Graduate Faculty Meeting, 1964 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Intensive Teacher Training Program, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Department Recommendations for PhD. Admissions, 1964; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Grading, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Curriculum, Instruction, and Supervision Program, 1964; 1965; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence- State Education Department, Division of Higher Education, 1964-1965; 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Graduate Assistantship and Fellowships, 1964; 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Campus Academic Plan, 1964-1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Curriculum, Instruction, and Supervision, Ed. D.-Minutes, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Provost, State University of New York-Harry Porter-Registration of Programs, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Graduate Admissions Policies, 1965; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Graduate Faculty- Minutes and Programs, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Schweitzer Chair Proposals, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Foreign Language Requirement- Evaluation, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - College of Arts and Sciences Curriculum Committee (1 of 2), 1965-1970; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - College of Arts and Sciences Curriculum Committee (2 of 2), 1965-1970; 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Committee to Advise the President on the Deanship of the School of Library Science, 1966; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Department of Librarianship, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - School Psychology Program- Operation, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Graduate School, Current Programs- Status, ca.1966 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Master Plan, 1964-1974; 1966; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Doctoral Dissertation Abstracts and Transmittals, 1966; 1967; 1968 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Exchange Programs-Strasbourg, Nanyang, Madrid, Cyprus, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Department of Business Education, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Memoranda to Deans, Chairman, Faculty, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Master Theses, 1967; 1968; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - School of Education- Curriculum and Instruction, 1967; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - School Of Social Welfare, Accreditation, 1967; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Cooperative Programs For Doctoral Study, 1967; 1968; 1969; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda to Graduate Academic Council, Studies and Reports(1 of 2), 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Memoranda to Graduate Academic Council, Studies and Reports(2 of 2), 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Operation- Review of New Programs, 1967; 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Department of Anthropology, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Afro-American Studies- Background materials, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Community-College Teacher Preparation Programs, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Programs Approved, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - EPDA Part E, 1968; 1969; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Masters Programs Under Review, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Teacher English as a Second Language-Internship, 1968; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Graduate Program Review Procedures, 1968; 1970; 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Council of Graduate School-Newsletter, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Campus Academic Plan, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Graduate Programs, proposed Doctoral Programs, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Master Plan(1971-1975), Priorities for the Albany and Space Science Department, 1969 October (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bureau of College Evaluation, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Council of Graduate Schools-Annual Meeting (1 of 2), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Council of Graduate Schools-Annual Meeting (2 of 2), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - School of Education- Department of Instruction - Instructional Assignments, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Teacher Preparation Programs, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - School of Business, 1969; Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Administrative Officials Meetings (1 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Administrative Officials Meetings (2 of 2), 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Black Studies-Annotated Bibliography and Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Budget Preparation, 1969; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Doctoral Programs Approved, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Graduate Programs-Information Copies, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Masters Programs Approved, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Operation-Review and Registration of New Graduate Programs, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Certification- Analysis, ca., 1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Assistantship/Fellowship Allocations(1 of 2), 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Assistantship/Fellowship Allocations(2 of 2), 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Operation-Registration of New Programs, 1970 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - EPDA Part E, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - NASA-Traineeship Program Proposal, 1970; Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Administrative Officials Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Advisory Search Committee for Vice President for Academic Affairs, 1970; 1971 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Department of Public Administration, 1970; 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda to Deans, Chairman, Faculty, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Operation Budget Information, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Programs in Manchester England and Madrid, Spain, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Graduate Programs- University Senate Action, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Records of J. Fredericks Volkwein, Assistant Dean, 1966-1977; 4; 0.66 cubic ft.
  This series contains records created by J. Fredericks Volkwein who served in a number of administrative positions at the University, including Assistant Dean of Graduate Studies. Materials include reports, meeting minutes, and correspondence. Topics covered by this series include evaluation and review of graduate programs, graduate grading policies, cross-registration, and other administrative functions of the Office of Graduate Studies.
  - Doctoral Programs - Education, 1966-1974; 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Selective Service and Veterans, 1968; 1969; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Doctor of Arts, 1969; 1970; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Grading - Graduate Pass/Fail Option, 1969; 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Grading - Graduate Policies, 1969-1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Graduate Program Evaluation, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Graduate Educational Policies, 1971; 1972; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Van Miller, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Task Force on Student Interchange(Cross-Registration) (1 of 2), 1971; 1972; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Task Force on Student Interchange(Cross-Registration) (2 of 2), 1971; 1972; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Conflict of Interest- Student/Employee, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Electric Company-Researcch and Development Center, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cross-Registration Graduate Proposals, 1972; 1973; 1974; 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)